<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AWS on Miro Sopanen</title><link>https://sopanen.net/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in AWS on Miro Sopanen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 15:07:13 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sopanen.net/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying FastAPI on AWS as a lambda container image</title><link>https://sopanen.net/posts/deploying-fastapi-on-aws-as-a-lambda-container-image/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 15:07:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sopanen.net/posts/deploying-fastapi-on-aws-as-a-lambda-container-image/</guid><description>Introduction 📌 Today we are setting up a serverless Lambda container image on AWS running FastAPI. It will be a single Lambda function with an API gateway endpoint attached to it. To handle internal routing we will use the library, Mangum.
Our Docker image will be registered on ECR and we will deploy it using the serverless framework. I&amp;rsquo;m super excited for this blog post since this is an awesome stack, so let&amp;rsquo;s start!</description></item><item><title>Deploying a serverless microservice with Flask &amp; Zappa</title><link>https://sopanen.net/posts/deploying-a-serverless-microservice-with-flask-zappa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 10:15:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sopanen.net/posts/deploying-a-serverless-microservice-with-flask-zappa/</guid><description>Intro 👇 In this blog post we are going to take a look at an awesome deployment tool called Zappa. We will deploy a serverless microservice using Flask on AWS in under 3 minutes. Exciting.
Our little microservice will be an API endpoint that returns a dataset of a random person in the form of a JSON response. You can view the source code here. Let&amp;rsquo;s start!
Prerequisites: You need an AWS account AWS CLI set-up on your development machine Virtualenv installed What is Zappa?</description></item><item><title>AWS Lambda function to retrieve Twitter follower count</title><link>https://sopanen.net/posts/aws-lambda-function-to-retrieve-twitter-follower-count/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 09:28:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sopanen.net/posts/aws-lambda-function-to-retrieve-twitter-follower-count/</guid><description>Intro 👇 One of my goals for this current year is to get more comfortable with AWS and get certified eventually. Therefore I will be trying out different things and blogging about it here.
I am starting out with a quite simple task and that is deploying an AWS Lambda function. In this case an AWS Lambda function that retrieves the count of your current Twitter followers.
Everytime the AWS API endpoint gets called, a Python script will run that will retrieve the current stats from the Twitter API and then returns it in JSON format so it can be easily used across systems.</description></item></channel></rss>